Our brain is probably the most important organ in our body.
我们的大脑可能是我们身体中最重要的器官。
It's an incredibly complex thing that helps us think, speak, feel and move.
它极其复杂，帮助我们思考、说话、感知和行动。
It's no wonder we need to look after it and just like the rest of our body, we need to keep it exercised to keep it healthy.
难怪我们需要照顾它，而且就像我们身体的其他部分一样，我们需要让它得到锻炼以保持健康。
Our brain is made up of 86 billion neurons - or nerve cells - but as we get older some of these slowly die off.
我们的大脑由860亿个神经元（即神经细胞）组成，但随着我们年龄的增长，其中一些会慢慢死亡。
In extreme cases, nerve cells in different areas of the brain become damaged and eventually die causing a condition called dementia where a person is unable to perform certain mental functions.
在极端情况下，大脑不同区域的神经细胞会受到损伤，最终死亡，从而导致一种叫做痴呆症的疾病，患者无法执行某些心智功能。
It's a good idea to train our brain by learning ways to increase our memory or intelligence.
通过学习提高记忆力或智力的方法来训练我们的大脑是个好主意。
I like to stretch my brain by doing a crossword or a Sudoku puzzle.
我喜欢通过做填字游戏或九宫格谜题来锻炼我的大脑。
There's also evidence that learning a second language can boost your brainpower.
也有证据表明，学习第二语言可以增强你的脑力。
Dr Catherine Loveday, who's a neuropsychologist, thinks being bilingual is a protective factor for the brain because it "involves a lot of switchings and that seems to exercise the sort of executive parts of our brain.
神经心理学家凯瑟琳·洛夫迪博士认为，成为双语者可以保护大脑，因为“这涉及到大量的转换，这似乎能锻炼我们大脑的执行区域。
Those parts of the brain are kind of stronger and fitter when it comes to resisting some kind of damage from a stroke."
当涉及到抵御中风所带来的某种损害时，大脑的这些部分会更强壮、更健康。”
The main aim of trying these skills is to stimulate the brain.
尝试这些技能的主要目的是刺激大脑。
This is something Dr. Loveday describes as building up our cognitive reserve - that's building up extra abilities to help protect the brain against declining memory or thinking.
洛夫迪博士将此描述为建立我们的认知储备——也就是培养额外的能力，以帮助保护大脑免受记忆力或思维能力下降的影响。
She says "even if people take up languages or take up other things later in life it will give them a degree of protection."
她说：“即使人们在晚年才开始学习语言或其他事情，这也会给他们一定程度的保护。”
As I get older, that has put my mind at rest!
随着我年龄的增长，这让我安心了不少！
The best bit of research I have read is that eating chocolate may enhance our ability to acquire and utilise knowledge - that's our cognitive performance.
我读过的最棒的研究是，吃巧克力可能会提高我们获取和运用知识的能力——也就是我们的认知表现。
It may not be healthy for the rest of my body but at least it might make me a brain box!
这对我身体的其他部分可能不健康，但至少它可能会让我成为一个聪明人！
What do you think?
你怎么看呢？